《POKÉMON 神探 Pikachu》
佢哋喺外面
They're outside.
警告，红色警戒
Alert. Condition: Red.
密闭室能源不足
We're losing power
in the containment chamber.
你听唔听到？
You hear that?
有嘢喺附近
Something's close.
就系呢种感觉，心跳加速
See? This is what I'm talking about.
My heart is pounding.
趴低
Get down, get down.
卡拉
Cubone.
系只卡拉卡拉？
A Cubone?
我哋唔系嚟帮你捉Pokémon
We're not catching you a Pokemon, are we?
﹣咩话？　　﹣话我知你冇预谋，杰克
What?
Tell me you didn't plan this, Jack.
﹣你讲咩呀？　　﹣老实讲，你系咪早有预谋
Jack, tell me
- you didn't plan this.    - Are you serious?
你斗胆质疑我？我梗系冇
How dare you. Okay? Of course not. Come on.
有少少啦
Okay, maybe.
㖊晚月圆　阿妈听到佢咿哇鬼叫
There was a full moon last night
and my mom heard it crying its eyes out.
佢以为我发恶梦　仲畀杯暖牛奶我饮
She thought I was having a nightmare,
so she brought me a glass of warm milk.
我以为你想同我散心
Dude, I thought you wanted to, you know, hang out
好似以前细个咁
and relive the good old days.
Like when we were kids.
我系呀，但系你睇吓佢
I do. But just look at it.
简直系为你而设嘅Pokémon
That is the perfect Pokemon for you.
杰克，我一早讲过　我唔想要Pokémon
Jack, I'm not looking for a Pokemon. I've told you this.
我谂过晒
I've thought long and hard about this, okay?
水系唔啱你，火系都唔啱　但系卡拉卡拉⋯
Water-type is not right for you.
Neither is Fire-type. But Cubone is--
﹣够孤独　　﹣冇错
Lonely.
Exactly.
杰克，真系多谢晒
Okay, thank you, Jack. Thank you for that.
仲有冇其他情感真相要揭晓？
Are there any other emotional truth-bombs
you wanna drop on me?
迟啲先讲，而家真相就喺我手中
Maybe later. But right now the truth is in my hands.
﹣畀个精灵球嚟　　﹣好，好！
- Just give me the Ball.    - Yes. Yes!
记住，捉Pokémon唔系靠技巧
Okay, remember, catching a Pokemon is not about skill.
所以你都可以
So you can do this.
多谢你支持
Good pep talk.
都要佢拣你　你要令佢想做你拍档，加油
Okay. It has to choose you, too.
So make it wanna be your partner.
喂，卡拉卡拉，你好吗？　你知嘛⋯
Hey, Cubone. What's up, buddy?
You know,
唔系个个都适合　戴住自己亲戚嘅骷髅头
not everyone can pull off
wearing the skull of their dead relative,
但系你衬得起
but, you know, you sure can.
唉，佢唔受
Okay, he didn't like that.
佢真系唔受
He did not like that.
杰克
Jack.
快啲抛！
Throw it!
抛精灵球
Throw the Ball.
畀啲男子气概
Like a man.
喔噢，卡拉
Uh-oh. Cubone.
卡拉！
Cubone!
得咗！
I did it!
仲未生锈
Still got it.
盏灯冇变绿色
The light's not green.
仲未变绿色　杰克，系咪唔妥？
It still hasn't turned green yet, Jack.
That's bad, right?
走呀！
Run!
﹣佢唔拣我！　　﹣走呀！
- It didn't choose me!    - Run!
﹣佢唔拣我呀，杰克！　　﹣睇得出！
- It didn't choose me, Jack!    - I can see that!
我唔啱佢心水！
I'm not its choice!
卡拉！
Cubone!
𠮶只卡拉卡拉好燥底　令我谂起我阿妈
That was one angry Cubone.
He reminded me a lot of my mom.
即系咁，我都唔想太老套⋯
So, um, I don't know if this is gonna sound
corny or whatever--
照直讲啦，杰克　我已经攰到冇力嬲
Just say it, Jack. I'm too tired to be angry.
我好担心你
I'm worried about you.
又嚟？
This again?
我哋识嘅人都搬走晒　我都就走
Hey, listen, everyone we know has left town
and now I'm leaving, too.
系，不过唔紧要
Yeah, but that's okay.
大家都要把握光阴　为自己著想，我都系
You gotta do what's best for you
with the time that you got.
大家都要把握光阴　为自己著想，我都系
That's what I'm doing.
我返工表现一流
You know, I'm crushing it at work.
应该就嚟升职
I'm gonna get a promotion real soon.
保险估价员可以升咩职？
What's the promotion for an insurance appraiser?
高级保险估价员？
"Senior insurance appraiser"?
我要升多两级先到高级
No, actually, that's two steps up
above where I'm at right now.
听到都想呕，咪玩啦
You're gonna make me throw up.
That's not a real thing.
终于收到讯号
Oh, I finally have service.
五个留言？点会有五个留言？
Wait, five voicemails?
Why would I have five voicemails?
可能系保险意外
Maybe it's an insurance emergency.
边个？
Who is it?
系莱姆市警局
Um, it's the Ryme City Police Department.
发生咗意外
There was an accident.
（车祸引发火灾，警探丧生）
唔好
Please don't.
Mmm.
我系话「唔该」，唔该你
I actually meant, "Please do". Thank you.
多谢晒，你条脷好「大方」
Thank you. You have a very generous tongue.
只大舌头系边个㗎？
Does this Lickitung belong to anyone?
有冇人认？
Anybody? No?
感谢你乘坐本列车
Thank you for travelling with us.
请收睇以下一段短片
Please sit back and watch this short informational video
欢迎你嚟到莱姆市
welcoming you to Ryme City.
一直以来　Pokémon系我哋世界嘅一部分
Throughout history,
Pokemon have been part of our world.
杰尼
Squirtle.
早期人类会捕捉佢哋
Early humans used to catch them
训练佢哋用特殊能力　造福人群
and train them to use their unique powers
for the common good.
时至今日，呢种关系进化成　Pokémon对战
This relationship evolved
into what we now refer to as Pokemon battles.
一个人改变咗呢一切
One man changed all of this.
霍华德克里佛　克里佛企业，创办人兼主席
Howard Clifford,
founder and chairman of Clifford Industries.
佢患有一种罕见退化症
Diagnosed with a rare degenerative disease,
自此辞去公司职务　周游世界寻找治疗方法
he resigned from his corporation
and searched the world for a cure.
到头来　我一直寻找嘅疗法
And it turned out that the cure I was looking for
其实就系要我自己　进化成一个更好嘅版本
was for me to evolve into a better version of myself.
我发现人同Pokémon嘅联系　可以达到呢一点
And I discovered how to do that
through a partnership with Pokemon.
佢想同全世界分享呢个发现
And he wanted to share that discovery with the world.
于是霍华德克里佛　建设咗莱姆市⋯
This is what inspired
Howard Clifford to build Ryme City,
一个人类同Pokémon　一齐生活嘅城市
a place where humans and Pokemon can live side by side.
其他地区嘅Pokémon　生活喺野外⋯
Unlike other regions, where Pokemon live in the wild,
但系呢度嘅Pokémon　同人类互助共存
here, we live and work together.
冇对战，冇训练员，冇精灵球
No battles. No Trainers. No Poke Balls.
一个更和谐、更团结嘅世界
A stronger, more harmonious world.
莱姆市全体市民欢迎你
From all our citizens: Welcome to Ryme City.
小火！小火龙！
Char! Charmander!
消防员同杰尼龟同心协力，扑灭火灾
Fighting fires wouldn't be the same
without their Squirtle partners.
杰尼，杰尼，杰尼，杰尼
Squirtle, Squirtle. Squirtle, Squirtle.
（吉田探长）
布鲁
Snubbull.
提姆，你好
Hi, Tim.
吉田探长
Lieutenant Yoshida.
你爸爸系精英中嘅精英
Your dad was the best of the best.
呢个环头嘅传奇人物
He was a legend in this precinct.
多谢你咁讲
Thank you. Thank you for saying that.
冇咗佢同埋佢拍档　实在可惜
It was a terrible tragedy, losing him and his partner.
﹣佢拍档？　　﹣佢只Pokémon
His partner?
His Pokemon.
我都唔知⋯
Oh, I didn't…
布鲁
Snubbull.
佢系咪嬲咗我？
I'm sorry, is yours mad at me?
﹣布鲁？　　﹣系呀
- Snubbull?    - Yeah.
佢外表可能好火爆
He may look grumpy on the outside,
但系内心其实软绵绵
but I assure you, he is adorable on the inside.
唔好介意我问　点解你冇Pokémon？
If you don't mind me asking,
how come you don't have a Pokemon?
我记得哈利讲过⋯
I thought I remember Harry saying
你自细就想做　Pokémon训练员
you wanted to be a Pokemon Trainer when you were young.
结果做唔成　而家做咗保险
Yeah, that didn't really work out.
Uh, I work in insurance now, so…
我明嘅
I understand.
但系提姆⋯
But, Tim,
希望你唔好太自责
please don't put this all on yourself.
一个人好难面对呢种情况
No one should go through this type of thing alone.
如果你同你爸爸有一丝相似⋯
If you are anything like your dad--
一丝都冇
I'm not.
我系婆婆养大嘅
I was just really raised by my grandmother.
你有冇佢屋企锁匙？　我想睇下有咩要处理
Do you have the spare keys for his apartment?
I should go wrap things up there.
当然
Of course.
冇问题
﹣呢个系佢地址　　﹣非常好
- Here's his address.    - Awesome.
﹣我可以带你去　　﹣唔使，我搞得掂，唔该
I can take you over if you want.
No. Nope. I'm all good. Thank you so much.
提姆
Tim.
呢份工⋯
This job,
负担好大
it demands a lot.
但系佢每日都挂住你
But you were on his mind every day.
呢个世界里面　你系佢最爱
He loved you more than anything else in the world.
好高兴认识你，探长
Uh, it was nice to meet you, Lieutenant.
唔好意思
Excuse me.
好啦
Okay.
（哈利古德曼）
可达！
Psyduck!
可达
Psyduck.
你想打劫定点？
Are you trying to rob me, or just annoy me?
﹣可达　　﹣佢系我拍档
- Psyduck.    - He's with me.
﹣我哋要倾倾　　﹣倾咩？
- We need to talk.    - We do?
我一直喺度等　等人打开𠮶个信箱
I've been waiting to see
who would open up that mailbox.
你涉入咗个非比寻常嘅故事
You just walked into quite a story.
呢种故事会令人恐惧　大家都怕恐惧
Stories like this spread fear. And they're afraid of fear.
但系我唔怕　我讲得出做得到
But I don't fear fear.
I walk the walk and I talk the talk.
我愿意不顾一切，揾出真相
And I'm willing to do whatever it takes
to get the honest scoop, and that's the hard truth.
唔好意思，妳边位？
I'm sorry. Who are you?
露丝史提芬，CNM记者
Lucy Stevens. Reporter for CNM.
咁细个就做记者？
Oh. You seem kinda young for that.
我帮CNM写部落格　Pokémon潮文，满意未？
I work for the CNM blog,
making Pokemon listicles all day, okay?
﹣十大最萌Pokémon　　﹣我婆婆好钟意睇
- Top 10 Cutest Pokemon.    - Yeah, my grandma loves those.
全部都萌㗎啦！
Yeah, news flash: they're all cute.
简直浪费我嘅记者才华
Such a waste of time
for someone with my nose for a story.
未得住，可达鸭　我攞紧料，等多阵啦
Oh, no, no, not now, Psyduck.
I'm working a source. Just one more minute.
好啦，我⋯
Okay, I'm gonna…
我要你接受访问　大爆哈利古德曼嘅情报
I'm gonna need you to go on record and tell me
everything you know about Harry Goodman.
咩话？
Wait, what?
哈利差少少就有重大发现
Harry was onto something big. Real big.
然后突然喺桥上发生车祸　我唔信
And then all of a sudden,
his car crashes over a bridge. I think not.
件事有内幕　我一定查到底
Something's rotten, and I'm gonna get to the bottom of it.
我对佢冇乜认识　已经多年冇见
Hey, look, I barely know the guy.
你只Pokémon呢？
- I haven't seen him in years.    - Where's your Pokemon partner?
我冇Pokémon　点解大家都咁问？
I don't have one. Why does everyone keep asking me that?
﹣一支公，九成有景轰　　﹣我走先
Loner. Probably hiding something.
Okay. I'm gonna go.
喂
Hey.
我只系无薪见习　但系我直觉敏锐
I may only be an unpaid intern,
but I can smell a story.
我会揾出真相
And I'm going to find it.
妳慢慢揾
Okay. You do that.
走啦，可达鸭
Come on, Psyduck. Let's go.
可达
Psyduck.
﹣边个？　　﹣有人吗？
Who is it?
Hello?
系我，蛇哥，我带咗货嚟
It's me. Snakes. I got the stuff.
摆喺门口，然后过主
Leave it on the doorstep
and get the hell out of here.
好呀，庄尼，但系我笔钱呢？
All right, Johnny, but what about my money?
仲系成日睇陈年侦探片
Still with the old detective movies.
（优秀公共服务奖）
（莱姆市遗迹发现古代梦幻残骸）
搞乜？
What?
咩嚟㗎？
What? What is that stuff?
（提姆古德曼收）
（21岁生日快乐）
（离芬镇 往 莱姆市）
「亲爱的提姆，如果你给我机会　我会做得更好」
"Dear Tim. I could do better if you give me a chance.
「我的大门随时为你打开」
I'll always have a place for you to stay."
6号月台列车⋯
The train on platform…
你爸爸会到火车站接你
Your father will pick you up from the station.
我唔去
I'm not going.
﹣咩话？　　﹣我唔想去
- What?    - I don't wanna go.
呢度系我屋企　我要留低陪婆婆妳
This is home. I wanna stay here with you, Grandma.
唔系啩
Oh, man.
（第24届神奥锦标赛）
今日系我人生最重要嘅日子
This is the most important day of my life.
我知道，提姆
I know, Tim.
但系你妈妈要去睇医生　唔可以等
But your mother had to see the doctor. It couldn't wait.
哈利
Harry.
系咪有人？
Someone there?
有冇人？
Hello?
Oh.
扭亲！
Ahh! That's a sprain.
Okay, okay, okay.
唔理你系边个⋯
Whoever you are,
我有武器
I know how to use this.
Pikachu？
It's a Pikachu?
惨，又系咁
Aw, jeez.
小朋友，你点入嚟㗎？
Hey, little guy, how did you get in here?
我知你唔明我讲乜
I know you can't understand me,
不过你放低钉书机
but put down the stapler,
否则我会电瓜你
or I will electrocute you.
你啱啱讲嘢？
Did you just talk?
哗！你听得明我？
Whoa. Did you just understand me?
咪住，你眼定定咁　肯定听得明
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
That is heavy eye contact right there. You heard me.
﹣冇呀　　﹣肯定有
- No, no, no.    - Yes, you did.
﹣好神奇！　　﹣唔好再讲！
- Oh, my God. This is amazing!    - Stop!
﹣你听得明我讲嘢　　﹣停！
- You can understand me.    - Stop talking. Stop!
我寂寞咗好耐
I have been so lonely.
﹣我想呕　　﹣咪呕住，细路，你要帮我
- I'm gonna throw up.    - No, kid. I need your help.
﹣我呕喇　　﹣我而家一身蚁，你听我讲
- I'm gonna throw up.    - I'm in serious trouble.
I need you to listen.
唔好意思，长尾怪手　我哋倾紧私人嘢
-No, no, no, no. Excuse me, Aipom,
we're having a private conversation here, please.
﹣咪讲嘢，你系幻觉！　　﹣幻觉你个头
Stop talking.
- You're a hallucination!    - You're a hallucination!
你快啲返出去！走呀！
And, you! Out! Shoo! Go!
小心啲，呢只嘢好唔妥
I'd tread lightly there, chief.
That Aipom don't look right.
喂！放开佢，衰马骝
Ahh!
No! Hey! Hey!
喂！放开佢，衰马骝
Get off him, whack-job.
细路快起身，佢扑过嚟
Get up, kid. He's coming back around.
听我讲，你要咬佢，尖叫
Okay, here's what you wanna do.
Okay, you wanna bite him. You wanna scream.
我哋玩大电视，唔玩唔玩
We're playing charades. We're not playing charades.
﹣我攞把刀先　　﹣唔要刀！
- Okay, I'm gonna get a knife.    - Not the knife!
得，唔要刀，揾过第样
Okay, bad idea with the knife. I'll find something else.
食生果！
Eat this!
唔使客气，睇落佢好饿
You are so welcome. He was just a hungry little guy…
弊家伙！
Oh, my God!
唔对路，走为上著
Come on, kid. Let's move.
上屋顶！
To the roof!
好主意！你顶住度门，我去求救
Brilliant idea! You hold the door.
- I'll go get help.    - What?
救命呀！救命呀！
Help! Help! Oh, my God! Help!
大镬！
Oh, sh…
救命呀！快啲嚟救人呀！
Help! Help! Oh, my God, help!
畀佢哋生吞喇！死喇佢！
Oh, he's being eaten alive! He's being eaten alive!
佢死梗喇！
A man is dying!
完全冇人理，个个见死不救
No one's coming. People are so insensitive.
快啲著返条裤，走啦
Uh-oh. Put your pants back on
and run like the wind.
快啲，快啲！
Blazing speed! Blazing speed!
你身上越少布　好似越吸引佢哋
No, they seem to be attracted to your increasing nudeness.
Okay.
好啦，呢度跳落去
All right, we're jumping down here.
唔得！我唔会跳落垃圾槽
No! No! I'm not going in the trash chute.
好主意，你即管留低陪佢哋
Good call. Let me know how it goes
with the super crazy Pokemon.
壮烈牺牲
You died a hero.
﹣落地几靓　　﹣唔好再烦我！
Way to stick the landing, kid.
Leave me alone!
班友好似下咗啖气
Oh. Looks like someone's back in a good mood.
走呀！长尾怪手癫咗呀！
Run! Rabid Aipom!
小心！快啲走！
Look out! Run!
快啲走！佢哋⋯
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! They're… Go! They…
你最好就著返条裤先
I think pants are gonna do you a lot of good right now.
走开！
Shoo! Go.
以为你会著三角裤　但系呢条都唔错
You know, I pictured you
as a bit of a briefs guy, but those are nice.
我就唔著底裤，豪迈啲嘛
Me? I don't wear underwear, you know? I'm not modest.
唔好意思，妳听唔听到佢讲乜？
Excuse me, excuse me, hi. Sorry.
Uh, you can hear him, right? You can hear him talking?
Pika﹣Pika
- Pika-Pika. Pika. Pikachu.    - Aw.
听到，Pika﹣Pika　佢好可爱
Yeah. Pika-Pika. Pika. He's adorable.
妳都好可爱　佢哋听唔明㗎
You're adorable. They can't understand me, kid.
系我，系我头先索咗𠮶啲嘢
It's me. It's that stuff that I put up my nose.
唔系妳谂𠮶啲，系气体　我索咗啲气体，只系意外⋯
Not like that. No, it was a gas.
- I was breathing gas.    - Hey, hey, hey.
唔系妳谂𠮶啲，系气体　我索咗啲气体，只系意外⋯
Accidentally. I was accidentally…
唔好再提索嘢
Ix-nay on the gas-ay.
因住拉你坐监，走啦
Unless you want Johnny Law to give you
a one-way ticket to the hoosegow, let's move.
﹣冇人听到？佢讲紧人话　　﹣我都系第一次
No one else can hear him?
This is a first for me, too, kid.
﹣冇人听到？佢讲紧人话　　﹣我都系第一次
He's saying words.
我讲嘢　个个都只听到「Pika﹣Pika」
Try to talk to people all the time.
All they hear is "Pika-Pika".
然后就摸我，锡我　揾手指笃我，好鬼核突
They pat me or kiss me,
stick a finger in me. It's really gross.
冇人听得明佢？你听唔明？　听唔明佢讲嘢？
Can no one else hear him?
Can you hear him talking? Do you hear him saying words?
点解你仲唔明？　得你一个明我
What are you not getting here, kid?
You're the only one who can hear me.
﹣系命中注定　　﹣唔系命中注定
- It's like destiny.    - It's not destiny.
﹣你点解会去𠮶间屋？　　﹣间屋系我阿爸屋企
Then why were you in that apartment?
It's my father's place. That's why I was there.
﹣你又点解喺𠮶度？　　﹣你系哈利个仔？
- Why were you there?    - You're Harry's son?
你点知佢个名？
How do you know his name?
（如寻获，请送还哈利古德曼）
你系哈利嘅Pokémon拍档？
You're Harry's Pokemon partner?
饮唔饮咖啡？
You want a coffee?
我想饮番杯，我哋去饮咖啡
'Cause I could use a coffee. I mean…
Yeah. Let's get a coffee.
嚟啦
Yeah. Come on.
（高帽咖啡馆）
当我清醒之后，严重失忆
So there I was in the middle of nowhere
with a bad case of the forgetsies.
过去嘅唯一线索　就系帽入面哈利个名同地址
The only clue to my past is Harry's name
and address inside this hat.
于是我跟住地址揾，就撞著你
So I made my way to the apartment
and that's when I found you.
胖丁胖丁
♪Jigglypuff♪
﹣我唔清楚，可能哈利牵涉太深　　﹣牵涉啲咩？
I don't know. Maybe Harry got in too deep.
Deep in what?
遇著班坏人，诸如此类　当差好常见
You know, mixed up with the wrong crowd,
that kinda thing. Happens to the best of us.
债台高筑，走投无路
The debts pile up. The walls close in.
白变黑，黑都系黑
Right becomes wrong. Wrong becomes wrong.
﹣你打畀边个？　　﹣冇人
- Wait, who you calling?    - No one.
听落唔错，份餐牌几好
Yeah, that sounds great. This menu looks really nice.
我唔明，你仲听到其他人讲嘢？
Wait, I'm confused.
Are you hearing other voices besides mine?
我净系想知道　我点解听得明你
All I wanna know is why I can understand you.
我帮你唔到　话咗我失忆，乜都记唔起
Ho! Can't help you there, kid.
Like I said, I have amnesia. Can't remember a darn thing.
所以你系只识讲嘢　但系失忆嘅Pikachu，仲有铺咖啡瘾
Okay, so you're a talking Pikachu
with no memories, who's addicted to caffeine.
我饮唔饮都得，自己话事
I could stop whenever I want. These are just choices.
整多杯，特浓，苦过廿四味　唔该，靓女
Another round. Extra shot.
Black as night. Thank you, sweetie.
乐天河童！
Ludicolo!
我系一流神探，不过冇咗记忆　就解唔开自己嘅谜团
Look, I'm a great detective.
But I can't solve my own mystery if I have no memory.
﹣你点知自己系侦探？　　﹣我骨子里感觉到
Then how do you even know you're a detective?
Well, I can feel that in my jellies.
﹣咩骨？　　﹣就系骨子里啰，你明唔明？
What is that? What is that?
It's the jellies. It's that thing, you know?
有时所有人都话你错
You feel it when you really believe in something
但系你好确定自己系啱
despite everyone telling you you're wrong.
所以我要揾番哈利　佢系我过去嘅关键
Which is why I need to find Harry.
He's the key to my past.
﹣乐天河童　　﹣唔该靓女
- Ludicolo.    - Thanks, doll.
我有坏消息，哈利已经死咗
I got some bad news for you 'cause, uh, Harry's dead.
咩话？冇可能　哈利肯定未死
What? No. No, no, no. No, Harry ain't dead.
哈利死咗，你估错，对唔住　我亲眼见到警察份报告
No, Harry is dead. You're wrong. I'm sorry.
I saw in the police report that he's dead.
﹣警察话佢死咗　　﹣即系法律上佢已经死亡
Just 'cause the cops say he's dead--
It means that he's legally dead.
系咩？有冇揾到尸体？
Really? Did they find a body?
梗系冇
Oh, I didn't think so.
份报告有冇话我都死咗？
And, by the way, did that report also say that I'm dead?
因为我生猛到爆　所以哈利都未死，讲完
'Cause if I'm still alive and kicking,
that means Harry's out there, too.
因为我生猛到爆　所以哈利都未死，讲完
Case closed.
﹣但系件事未完，因为我要破案　　﹣好呀，我陪你玩，破咩案？
But still open until I solve it.
Okay, I'll bite. Solve what?
多谢你陪我玩，即系咁
Oh, I'm glad you're gonna bite.
All right. Here it is.
哈利伪造自己死亡
Harry faked his own death.
或者有人伪造佢嘅死亡
Or somebody else faked Harry's death.
或者哈利伪造人哋死亡
Or Harry faked somebody else's death.
最尾个猜测唔合理　但系头两个猜测几好
That last one doesn't work at all.
- No, it doesn't.    - The first two are contenders.
﹣我走喇，我哋讲完　　﹣我哋未讲完
No, I'm gonna go. We're done here.
- No, we are not done here.    - This is…
等阵，你去边呀？
Wait. Wait. Wait a minute. Where're you going?
咪走住，我哋需要大家
Hold up a sec. We're gonna need each other.
错晒！我唔需要Pokémon，讲完
No, we don't. I don't need a Pokemon. Period. Got it?
世界一流神探呢？
Then what about a world-class detective?
如果你想揾番老窦，我系最佳选择
Because if you wanna find your pops, I'm your best bet.
世界一流神探应该一早知道
I think a world-class detective
oughta have figured out by now
我唔系嚟揾我老窦
that I'm not here to find my father.
我系嚟同佢道别
I'm here to say goodbye.
唔使咁早道别住
Hey, hey. There's no one to say goodbye to.
你谂谂，你可以同人类沟通
Look, you can talk to humans. I can talk to Pokemon.
我就同Pokémon沟通　我哋彼此可以沟通
We can talk to each other.
正常根本唔会发生　肯定有特别意义
This doesn't happen, kid. It has to mean something.
有一种魔法令我哋一齐　系叫「希望」
There's magic that brought us together,
and that magic is called hope.
希望哈利仲在生
Hope that Harry is still alive.
你骨子里都感觉到呢？
Oh, you feel it. You feel it in your jellies, don't you?
我骨子里乜都冇
There's nothing in my jellies.
我哋两个一定得
We're gonna do this. You and me.
我唔敢相信⋯
I can't belie…
﹣听朝喺度等　　﹣好
I will meet you here tomorrow morning.
Great.
﹣你去边？　　﹣返我屋企
- Where're you going?    - To my apartment.
﹣咩叫「你屋企」？　　﹣咩呀？
What do you mean, "Your apartment"?
What?
﹣好啦，畀张梳化你瞓　　﹣我唔要瞓梳化
All right, you can sleep on the couch.
No, I'm not gonna sleep on the couch.
一系瞓炉头啦　麻烦你开开门
Well, then you can sleep on the stove.
Be a dear, would you, and get the door for me.
﹣我到底做紧乜？　　﹣我竟然邀请人嚟过夜
What am I doing?
I just invited
﹣我到底做紧乜？　　﹣我竟然邀请人嚟过夜
someone to my apartment.
我平时唔会咁　我唔系啲咁随便嘅Pokémon
I never do this. I'm not that kind of Pokemon.
周围铺满尘，但冇指纹
Dust everywhere.
No fingerprints.
唔合理
Ugh. Doesn't add up.
﹣你搞紧咩？　　﹣我揾紧过去嘅线索
What is going on in here?
I'm searching the joint, looking for clues.
﹣呢间房你㗎？　　﹣唔系
- Is this your room?    - No.
﹣哈利有冇其他仔女？　　﹣冇
Does Harry have other children?
No.
我细个时，佢想我喺度住　所以布置到好似我细个间房咁
He wanted me to live here when I was a kid,
so he made it look like my childhood room.
不如讨论吓　你细个瞓Pikachu床？
Should we talk about the fact
that your childhood bed is a Pikachu bed?
咁啱啫
It's a coincidence.
唔好意思，麻烦你大声讲　我听唔清楚
I'm sorry. Can you speak up?
I can't hear you.
我未试过　同时觉得荣幸同惊恐
I've never been so flattered
and creeped out at the same time.
﹣你会唔会将我整做灯罩？　　﹣可能会
Are you gonna make me into a lampshade?
Oh, I might.
咪住，咁多Pokémon卡　仲有对战海报⋯
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
All these Pokemon cards and the battle posters…
肯定有关系
There's a connection, isn't there?
﹣你钟意Pokémon　　﹣唔系
- You love Pokemon.    - No.
肯定系
Yeah. Yeah, you do.
已经好耐以前　之后我阿爸搬咗入城
That was a long time ago,
before my father moved to the city
宁愿陪Pokémon　都唔陪自己个仔
and spent more time with Pokemon than his own son.
好呀，怪晒你老窦啦
Mmm, yeah, blame it on your dad.
睇睇呢个人　一屋都系佢嘅相
Okay, look, what about this?
There's pictures of her all over the apartment.
佢好明显同哈利有关系　可能会识我
She's obviously connected to Harry.
She might know me.
可能系线索
She could be a lead.
一定唔会
No, she's not.
呢个系我妈妈
That's my mom.
我11岁𠮶年佢已经过咗身
She passed away when I was 11.
对唔住
Oh. I'm sorry. I…
我唔知道
I didn't realize.
听朝我带你去揾吉田　睇吓揾唔揾到答案
Tomorrow morning I'm gonna take you to Yoshida
so we can get some answers.
我啲线索！
Ahh, my clues!
﹣呢啲咩嚟㗎？　　﹣我努力嘅成果
What is all this?
Hard work. That's what this is.
仲有，唔好揾警察　要先搞清楚边个信得过
And, by the way, we can't go to the cops.
Not till we know who we can trust.
执返好我啲线索
So put my clues back in order, would you?
呢啲唔叫线索，系连环杀手所为
These aren't clues. This is the work of a serial killer.
﹣几乎系线索　　﹣咩意思？
They're almost clues.
What does that even mean?
我想触发记忆，谂番旧事　摊开晒会有帮助
Trying to jog my memory, retrace my steps.
It helps me to see it all laid out.
于是揾到佢　法国人会话系火热线索
That's how I found this.
This is what a Frenchman would callcaliente fiesta.
唔系法文
Not French.
﹣闻我手指　　﹣我唔会闻你手指
Smell my finger.
I will never smell your finger.
冇胆鬼
Coward.
重点系寻晚袭击我哋班长尾怪手　身上有呢支R物质嘅味
The point is, I smelled this R stuff
on those Aipom when they attacked us yesterday.
﹣R？　　﹣冇错！
- R?    - Bingo!
大突破
La Cucaracha.
哈利查嘅案件　应该有重大突破
See, I'm thinking Harry
caught a break in the case,
所以幕后黑手派人将佢灭口
forcing our shadowy kingpin
to send out hired goons to deliver the big hush-hush.
我哋要追溯哈利嘅步伐　然后自己破案⋯
We need to retrace Harry's steps.
Either solve the case ourselves
或者有足够进展逼大魔头现身
or get far enough along that this
A-number-one bad guy has to reveal himself.
﹣可能系女魔头　　﹣唔好再搞盏灯
- Or herself!    - Can you stop doing that?
第一步应该点行？
So, what is the way in, huh?
答案就喺呢间房入面
The answer is in this room.
呢间唔叫房，简直系火警高危区　周围都系垃圾废纸⋯
This isn't a room. This is a fire hazard.
It's just junk and papers and…
（Pokémon巡游筹备）
同报纸
Newspapers.
你谂到咩？
What you got, kid?
我最近识咗个人　佢喺CNM做初级记者
I literally just met someone.
She was a… She was a junior reporter at CNM.
佢调查紧哈利　应该有嘢隐瞒
She was doing a story on Harry.
I think she knows more than she let on.
聪明人通常都会隐瞒
The smart ones always do.
我哋去佢公司，撬开佢把口
We gotta go down to her work and press her.
﹣只系打个比喻　　﹣我知咩系比喻
- Okay.    - That's a metaphor.
Yeah, I know what a metaphor is.
我未饮完
Uh, I was drinking that.
𠮶杯都未饮⋯随便踩啦　只不过系我毕生成就
I was also drink… Just step anywhere.
It's only my life's work.
唔得，唔好爬上嚟
No. No, we're not doing that.
算，我自己行
Fine, I'll walk.
反正我想呢个钟头　行够十万步
I'm trying to get in 100,000 steps this hour.
大家好，我系CNM总裁　兼克里佛企业主席罗杰克里佛
Hello, I'm Roger Clifford, president of CNM
and chairman of Clifford Enterprises.
而我就系建立莱姆市嘅梦想家　霍华德克里佛
And I'm Howard Clifford,
the visionary icon behind Ryme City.
为咗宣扬和谐嘅精神
Together, in the spirit of harmony,
我哋将会举办莱姆市史上　最大型嘅巡游，请勿错过
we're throwing the largest parade
that Ryme City has ever seen.
我哋将会举办莱姆市史上　最大型嘅巡游，请勿错过
You won't wanna miss it.
今个周末，我哋邀请所有人
So, at the weekend, we invite the people…
同所有Pokémon一齐出席
And the Pokemon to be there.
庆祝人类同Pokémon和谐共处
A celebration of the harmony
between humans and Pokemon.
搞掂！
And, cut!
﹣我觉得唔错　　﹣收声啦，老窦！
Well, I think that went rather well.
Oh, shut up, Dad!
几好仔㖞
He seems nice.
罗杰你咪咁啦　呢个系我哋送畀市民嘅礼物
Roger, please. This is supposed to be
our gift to the citizens.
梦想家？你系咪讲笑？
"Visionary icon"? Really?
不如直接叫「救世主」啦？
Was "savior of the world" taken?
份稿系你啲人写㗎
It was your people who wrote the promo, son.
系咪有份完整版　讲你点医好癌症？
Oh, is there an unabridged version
where you cure cancer?
好呀，转身走啰　你次次都系咁
Oh, that's right, yeah.
Turn your back on me like you always did.
﹣百变怪！　　﹣根本冇人钟意你只Pokémon！
Ditto!
By the way, no one likes your Pokemon!
佢喺𠮶边
There she is.
﹣我明白你点解咁兴奋　　﹣我冇兴奋
I can see why you were so excited.
I was… Okay, I was not that excited.
克里佛先生！克里佛先生！
Mr. Clifford! Mr. Clifford!
克里佛先生，我可能有大新闻
Mr. Clifford, I may have a story for you.
我听讲有Pokémon攻击人类　但系主流媒体冇报导
I've heard rumors of Pokemon attacking people.
But there's been no mainstream coverage.
唔好意思，我哋唔系八卦杂志
I'm sorry, we're not a tabloid.
唔会报导呢啲　冇根据嘅流言蜚语
Which means that we don't report
on rumors, gossip or hearsay.
确认唔到嘅就唔系新闻
It's not news if it can't be verified.
你要报导新闻　就要揾可靠嘅料
You want a story, find a source.
仲有专业意见醒妳
Oh, and pro tip:
著衫要著得好好睇睇
A reasonable sense of fashion.
佢行过嚟，整返个深奥嘅款
Here she comes.
Here she comes. Try to look deep.
你点会喺度？
What are you doing here?
我哋又见面
Hey, again. Uh…
我知道有啲怪　但系我有问题要妳解答
Yeah, I know this seems weird
but I actually needed to ask you something.
我而家唔系好方便
Now's not really a good time.
我都有见到，唔好意思
Yeah, I saw that. I'm sorry.
对唔住，杯嘢好热
Sorry. It's piping hot.
你揾到Pokémon做你拍档
You found yourself a Pokemon partner.
唔算系
- Not exactly, no.    - Aw.
佢好得意
He's cute.
佢想色诱我，但系唔使担心　我定力十足⋯
She's trying to work me, kid. But, trust me, I can…
救命，好舒服
Oh, sweet Mother of Arceus, that feels so good.
﹣即系咁⋯　　﹣舒服死我
- So, listen…    - Oh, my God.
发生咩事？
What happened?
我喺哈利书台揾到呢支嘢　差啲搞到我窒息，我⋯
I found something in Harry's desk,
nearly choked me to death, and I was--
隔墙有耳
No, not here.
去我办公室倾
In my office.
去佢办公室？　我哋要去佢办公室？
In her office? We're going to her office?
好地方吖
This is great.
呢个唔叫办公室　叫摆咗铅笔嘅棺材
This isn't an office. It's a coffin with pencils.
可达？
Psyduck?
冇错，佢听得明我　我听得明佢，我哋天赋异禀
Yeah, that's right. I can talk to the kid,
he can talk to me. We're gifted.
你冇话我知佢有可达鸭　佢哋压力太大就爆炸
You didn't tell me that she has a Psyduck.
These things explode when they're stressed.
冷静啲
Hey. Hey, keep calm, pal.
冇事嘅，冇事嘅
Serenity now. Serenity now.
唔喺度
- No.    - Okay.
Okay.
﹣揾到？　　﹣喺度
- You got it?    - Here it is.
妳点揾到㗎？
Where did you find these?
听讲哈利喺码头有个线人
Word on the street was that
Harry had an informant near the docks.
我去咗调查　之后就揾到啲樽仔
I went there to snoop around,
and that's where I found the vial.
但系码头好危险
But the docks can be dangerous.
唔适合夜妈妈一个人去
It's not the sort of place
you want to visit alone at night.
我夜晚一个人出街都好掂
I'm actually pretty good at being alone at night.
完全捉错用神
Nope, that did not land right at all.
我唔系咁嘅意思
That's not… That's not what I meant to say. Um…
﹣唔紧要　　﹣我都系⋯
- It's okay.    - I'm just gonna…
我哋走先
We should go.
﹣早走早著　　﹣我会侧侧身出去
- Yeah, we should go.    - I'm just gonna scoot by ya.
你系咪成世人未沟过女？
Good God, have you ever talked to a woman before?
﹣你背脊⋯　　﹣可达
- You've got some…    - Psyduck.
我沟过女，唔使你帮
Yes, I've talked women before. No, I don't need your help.
出世𠮶阵沟护士？
Was it during the birth canal, or…
知唔知你需要咩？　一个肩鞍，肯定有得淘
You know what you need?
A shoulder saddle. I bet someone makes one.
你实有其他办法走动　家阵我好样衰
Okay. There are other ways for you to get around.
This is humiliating.
你一步等于我一千步　我个肺提子咁细粒
Every step for you is 1000 for me,
and my lungs are the size of grapes.
我哋做拍档　首先要约法三章
We need to get some ground rules
if this partnership's gonna work.
﹣你唔系我拍档　　﹣导师、师傅、良师益友
You're not my partner.
Mentor,sensei,master,
﹣任你拣　　﹣全部都唔系
whatever you wanna call it.
可能唔系啲气体？　或者系遗传
Nope, none of those.
Hey, what if it wasn't the gas? What if it's hereditary?
可能哈利都听得明你把麻烦声
What if Harry could understand your annoying voice, too?
你唔讲出口我哋都明　我感应到你想讲咩
You don't need to talk to us for us to understand.
We can feel what you're saying.
你要抛开成见，多啲尝试
You have to be open to the experience. Try it sometime.
唔使客气，同你讲嘢已经够烦
Yeah, I'd rather not.
I got my plate full talking to you.
系咩嚟？
What is that?
无声臭屁，唔好意思　我饮得太多咖啡，搞肚痛
Silent but deadly.
Apologies, my tummy's bad from all the coffee.
好核突，快啲落地
No. Ew. Get off.
我讲佢
I meant that.
Oh. Ooh. Ugh.
佢？
That.
系魔墙人偶，我至憎佢哋
It's a Mr. Mime. They're the worst.
粒声唔出，但系烦到死
Silent but annoying.
佢系咪认得你？　佢好似认得你
Does he recognize you? I think he recognizes you.
我系哈利拍档　可能同佢交过手
Well, I was Harry's partner, so I would've been with him.
哈利个线人系Pokémon！
Harry's informant is a Pokemon!
捉住佢！
Get him!
﹣佢根本都冇跑　　﹣唔好话佢听
- He's barely moving.    - Don't tell him that.
佢踩电单车走喇
Oh! He's on a bike.
佢以为自己走得甩　走去佢前面
Come on! He thinks he's getting away.
Look, quick! Get in front of him.
﹣截停佢，你得嘅　　﹣停呀
- Cut him off. You can make it.    - Stop.
大剂，佢撞得好应
Oh, no.
He's going down hard, Tim.
鬼叫佢唔戴头盔
Should've worn a helmet.
希望佢大步槛过
I hope he makes it.
够喇，咪玩
Come on. This is ridiculous.
﹣我哋扮警探，我忠你奸　　﹣我哋唔系警探
I'm good cop, you're bad cop.
We're not cops.
大胆啲啦，你大只过我　唔打得都睇得
Grow some berries.
You're bigger and tougher looking than I am.
企直啲
Stand up straight!
听住，我哋有办法　令你开声或者做手势
Listen up.
We got ways to make you talk. Or mime.
﹣冇错　　﹣快啲爆料
Yeah.
So tell us what we wanna know.
哈利古德曼点解会嚟呢度？　同R有咩关系？
Why was Harry Goodman here
and what did it have to do with the R?
管，罐！
Pipe. Yes, okay. A can!
撞？推？
Shoving. Pushing.
我问题系我拒人千里　之后又唔想人走
My problem is that I push people away
and then hate them for leaving.
﹣佢叫你折埋　　﹣咩话？叫我折埋？
- He's saying you can shove it.    - What? I can shove it?
够喇！我哋调转角色　我做奸探，你做忠探
Okay, that's it. We're switching roles.
I'm bad cop, you're good cop.
我哋唔系警探！
- No, no, no, we're not cops!    - Oh!
救命，撞到应
Oh, God, that's a very hard wall.
系㖞，魔墙人偶识整透明力墙
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, Mr. Mime has the ability
to make invisible walls.
我知呀，我都系Pokémon　你唔记得咗？
Uh, yes, I know. I happen to be a Pokemon, too, remember?
哈利谂到办法套佢口供
Look, Harry figured this guy out somehow.
应该系靠心理战
I think the trick is getting inside his head.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
你想点？
What are you doing?
咩事？
Oh, what's this?
原来有度门，隐咗形我冇见到
Oh, there's a door there. I didn't…
Probably because it's invisible.
冇错，而家我入咗你空间
Huh? Yeah! I'm in your space now, am I right?
系咪觉得好唔舒服？
You don't like this so much, do you?
你搞乜？
What are you doing?
拎住个水壶，倒紧水
That's a jug. No, you're pouring.
唔系
No.
系盐，你拎住罐盐煮𩠌
Salt. It's a salt shaker. You're cooking.
真厨艺系由心出发，唔靠食谱
- No.    - Real cooking is about
following your heart, not a recipe!
你讲乜呀？
What are you talking about?
汽油，你倒紧汽油
Gas. You're pouring gasoline on…
哗，即刻好黑暗
- Mmm-hmm.    - Oh, that went dark fast.
我钟意，我好钟意
I like this. I like this very much.
好呀，好呀
All right, all right.
你想玩游戏，我同你玩
Okay. You wanna play that game?
I can play that game.
你觉得好笑咩？
You think that's funny?
你系咪觉得好好笑？
You think that's funny, huh?
睇你笑得几耐
You're not gonna be laughing soon, huh?
而家仲笑唔笑得出？
Who's laughing now, huh?
我明你想点
Oh. Oh, I smell what you're stepping in.
冇错，魔墙人偶
That's right, Mr. Mime.
你唔快啲爆料　因住变脆香人偶
You're about to be Mr. Melt
unless you start talking.
卡，啤牌、扑克
Cards, cards. Playing cards. Poker.
应该系讲紧R
No, I think he's talking about the R.
有人周围派R
Someone was handing out R.
手势清楚啲，边度？
Use your body words. Where?
圆形屋、月亮屋、月亮、屋
Circle house. Moon house. Moon. House.
玩够喇，讲啦
Enough with the games. Say it.
开口讲啦
Just say it!
开声讲呀，蠢材！
Talk, you stupid mime!
冷静啲
Okay, just relax.
圆
Uh, round.
圆形屋
Round house. Uh…
啲R系来自圆屋！
The source of the R came from the Roundhouse.
唔错，睇嚟你有啲侦探天分
Yeah, nice work, kid. Maybe there's
a little detective in you after all.
击中要害！额外伤害！
Critical hit! Additional damage!
（加农水炮！）
我以为莱姆市冇Pokémon对战
I didn't know they had Pokemon battles in Ryme City.
系唔应该有㗎
We're not supposed to.
耿鬼使出暗影球！
Gengar uses Shadow Ball!
嚟啦，我哋周围睇睇
Come on. Let's take a look around.
（个细路嚟咗，仲带埋Pikachu）
我哋总结一吓案情
Okay, kid. So here's what we know.
哈利追寻R到呢度
Harry traces the R to here.
之后佢成日嚟　因为呢度某人知道某啲嘢
Then frequents this joint because someone
here knows something about something.
我哋只要揾出𠮶个人，同𠮶啲嘢
We just need to find the someone and the something.
𠮶只Pikachu个拍档呢？唔好走
Hey, hey! Where's that Pikachu's partner? Don't go.
照我睇　系我哋畀人揾到
I think the "someone" just found us.
我想知佢上啲咩网
Wow. I'd like to see
this guy's Internet search history.
你系边个？
Who are you?
顺水推舟，话你系我新拍档
Let's see where this goes.
Tell him you're my new partner.
我系佢新拍档
I'm his new partner.
𠮶只Pikachu招十万伏特
Well, that Pikachu's Thunderbolt
上次差啲打残我只宝贝喷火龙
almost wrecked my prize Charizard
- last time he was here.    - Oh.
伤痕仲未退
Scar is still fresh.
我只系睇到两块大胸肌　一个字都冇听到
All I hear are consonants, and all I see are nipples.
你知嘛？
And you know what?
佢整烂咗我件外套，你睇
He ruined my coat, man. Look at this.
﹣唔好意思　　﹣毋理外套，佢点解唔著衫？
I'm so sorry.
Forget the coat. Where's his shirt?
呢度系我地头！
This! This is my place!
冇人可以踩入我地头
And nobody comes into my place
咁样对我嘅Pokémon
and does that to my Pokemon.
你望咩呀？
What are you looking at?
仲有我件外套
Or to my coat.
系㖞，外套
Right, the coat. The coat.
你做乜呀？
What are you doing?
同佢互睥，眨眼先就输
Classic staredown, kid. First one to blink loses.
咪再骚扰我
Now stop distracting me.
我只系想知佢旧拍档　点解会嚟呢度
Er, look, I just wanna know
why his old partner was here. That's all.
耿鬼胜
Gengar wins.
预备下场对战
Ready for next battle.
我要重赛
And I want a rematch.
你肯同我重赛
You give me my rematch…
我就话晒我知嘅嘢你听
I'll tell you everything you want to know. What I know.
同佢讲冇问题，老友
- Er…    - Tell him he's on,amigo.
好
Okay.
下场对战即将开始
A new battle's unfolding.
Pikachu大战喷火龙
Pikachu versus Charizard.
重赛！
Rematch!
帮我拎住顶帽
Here. Hold my hat.
预备睇我表演
I'm about to rock this place.
﹣好　　﹣喷火龙！喷火龙！
- Okay.    - Charizard! Charizard!
拉拉筋先，费事阵间抽筋
Just doing some light stretching.
You never wanna go into these things tight.
你今次一定要赢
You're gonna win this time, okay?
你做咩？打算点攻击？
What are you doing? What is your plan of attack?
我冇乜打算，一切随机应变
I don't operate according to plans, kid.
I deal with things in the moment.
嚟，索一索，然后落场
Here. Here we go. Now you'll be ready.
好明显，我收拾过呢只蠢嘢
Now, obviously, I've dealt with this putz before,
我会将案件重演
so I'll just do it again.
畀返顶帽我！
Give me my hat back!
𠮶只嘢队咗劲大支R物质！
That thing just chugged
a year's worth of that R stuff!
你头先都话过
Hey, hey, hey. It's like you said, okay?
你之前赢过一次　出绝招打佢就得
You did it before.
You just gotta use your powers.
你可以用电光一闪　放电或者电球⋯
You can use Quick Attack, Discharge, or Electro Ball,
但系伏特攻击最适合　用𠮶招先啦
but I think Volt Tackle
is your best move, so start with that.
首先，你几时学识做Pokémon训练员？
First of all,
when did you learn how to be a Pokemon Trainer?
第二，快啲放我出去！
And secondly, get me the hell out of here!
开战！
Begin!
﹣小心！　　﹣死喇⋯
- Look out!    - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
我已经唔记得你讲过咩！
I forgot everything you said!
我有失忆症，记性好差！
I forget things, it's what I do! I have amnesia!
你要击中要害，用伏特攻击！
You need to go for a critical hit. Use Volt Tackle!
伏特攻击会两败俱伤　我都系用十万伏特
Volt Tackle will knock me out. I'm going for Thunderbolt.
好，你得㗎！
Come on. You got it, you got it!
快啲啦⋯
Come on, come on, come on.
老友，你见点呀？
Hey, bud! What are you doing?
有人睇住，我出唔到电！　大家不如拧转面？
I can't do it when people are watching.
Can everyone just look away, please?
唔得，我唔记得咗点出招
It's not working.
I forgot how to use my powers.
但系佢记得！
But he didn't!
Pikachu，走呀！
Pikachu, run!
死喇⋯
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
一招就打到飞起！
Taken out with one hit!
哎呀，Pikachu，系咪想喊？
Aw, Pikachu. Wanna cry?
你唔会咁做，我咁可爱！
You don't wanna do this! I'm adorable.
Pika﹣Pika？
Pika-Pika?
你癫咗？快啲出嚟！
Are you crazy? Get out of there!
等我出招！
I got it, kid!
你想对我宝贝做咩呀？
What are you doing to my baby?
﹣行开呀！　　﹣弊
- Get out of the way!    - Uh-oh.
今次大镬
Uh-oh. That's not good.
快啲爆料！
Tell me what you know!
你哋揾𠮶个人　想查出R嘅来源
The guy you are looking for
wanted to know the source of R.
R嚟自博士　我净系知咁多，放我走！
It comes from the doctor.
That's all I know.
R嚟自博士　我净系知咁多，放我走！
Now let me go!
接得好，我哋要离开呢度
Nice catch, kid. Let's get out of here.
我有个计划
I got a plan.
搞咩？咪玩啦，鲤鱼王冇鬼用
What? That's not gonna work. Magikarp is the worst.
鲤鱼王一进化就系暴鲤龙　只需要踢佢一踢
Magikarp can evolve into Gyarados.
All it needs is a little kick.
嚟啦！
Water in the hole!
我脑入面个结果唔系咁
In my head, I saw that differently.
Er…
提姆？我唔识浮水
Hey, Tim? I don't float.
话咗鲤鱼王唔系冇用
Ha! I told you Magikarp weren't useless.
你已经被拘捕
You're under arrest.
我以为你赶住返屋企
I thought you couldn't wait to get home.
系呀，但系计划有变　因为我揾到佢
Yeah. Well, my plans changed because I found him.
我唔明
I'm not following.
哈利未死，佢只Pokémon拍档仲在生　代表佢都一样
Harry's not dead. If his Pokemon partner
is still alive, that means he is, too.
呢啲唔算证据
That is not proof, son.
﹣话佢知R单嘢　　﹣等阵
Tell him about the chemical R.
Give me a minute.
哈利最后一单案　同地下对战有关
Harry's last case
had to do with those underground battles.
我哋去𠮶度　揾到种化合物
That's why I was there. There's a chemical.
我哋调查过
We ran an investigation.
﹣哈利有发现，于是惹祸　　﹣𠮶单案已经完咗！
Harry figured it out and he's in trouble.
That case is closed. Over!
你要继续调查！　佢未死，我感觉到
You gotta reopen the investigation!
He's out there, I can feel it.
﹣骨子里，讲啦　　﹣我唔会讲
In your jellies. Go ahead, say it.
I'm not gonna say that.
探长，我⋯骨头深处都感觉到
I can feel it, Lieutenant, in my bones.
﹣骨子里好啲　　﹣够喇！
- Not as good.    - Stop!
仲有我听得明Pikachu讲嘢　每个字都一清二楚
Oh, yeah, and I can understand Pikachu,
like, word perfect, so…
提姆
Tim.
失去至亲系沉重打击　逃避都好正常
It's very difficult coping with loss.
Denial can be a powerful thing.
我冇逃避，我知道我系啱！
No, I'm not in denial! I'm right, I know it!
佢仲未死
He's… He's out there.
我一直唔想畀你睇⋯
I never wanted to show you this,
但系我谂你应该睇吓
but I think it's important you see it.
咁严重嘅车祸，冇人可以生还
No one could survive a crash like that.
你爸爸都一样
Not even your dad.
佢走咗喇，提姆
He's gone, Tim.
我应该坐𠮶班火车
I should've gotten on that train.
唔明
What's that, kid?
我妈妈死咗之后
After my mom died,
我同我爸爸就开始疏远
my dad and I drifted apart.
Er…
佢搬咗嚟呢度，搏命工作
He moved here and poured himself into his work.
后来佢想我搬嚟同佢住
And, eventually, he tried to get me
to come live with him,
但系我唔肯
but I wouldn't go.
点解？
How come?
我以为佢唔在乎
I didn't think he cared.
我谂我习惯咗冇佢喺身边
I guess I just got used to him not being around
而且一直都冇原谅佢
and I couldn't forgive him for it.
直至我嚟到呢度
Until I got here.
我发现佢其实好在乎
And I realized that he did care.
但系我一直唔知道
But I didn't know…
因为我从来冇畀机会佢
because I never gave him the chance.
而家已经太迟
And now it's too late.
我真系⋯
I really…
我真系希望我有上𠮶班火车
I really wish I'd gotten on that train.
Mmm-hmm.
听住
Listen, kid.
Um…
我可能失咗忆⋯
Look, I may not have memories,
但系有一件事我好清楚
um, but I know this much:
呢件事唔系你嘅错
It wasn't your fault.
唔系任何人嘅错
It wasn't anybody's fault.
我肯定，如果你爸爸喺度⋯
And I'm sure that if your dad was here,
佢会出尽力揽你，揽到你骨折
he would hug you so hard,
your bones would pop.
然后佢会向你道歉
And he'd tell you
he's sorry for everything.
佢肯定以你为荣
He'd be damn proud of you, kid.
我一直都对你唔系几好
I haven't been really nice to you.
真系冇好过
No, you really haven't.
咁⋯
Well…
﹣我哋仲有一个谜团要破解　　﹣咩谜团？
We still got one mystery to solve.
What?
你嘅谜团
Yours.
我哋去调查　边个搞成你咁
Let's find out who did this to you.
帮你恢复记忆
Get your memory back.
好呀
I'd like that.
最好不过
I'd like that very much.
一睇就知系反派嘅车
Well, that's a bad-guy car.
唔该妳，洛曼小姐
Thank you, Miss Norman.
系呀，唔该妳　洛曼小姐，妳可以走啦
Yes. Thank you, Miss Norman. That'll be all.
佢哑嘅？
What a blabbermouth.
请入嚟
Please, come in.
佢哋系咪好神奇嘅生物？
Magnificent creatures, aren't they?
火伊布
Whoa. A Flareon.
试想像，如果你可以进化⋯
Imagine being able to evolve
变成最理想嘅自己
into the best possible version of yourself.
你好
Hmm. 'Sup?
体内嘅潜能　等住你去触发
That greatness inside you, just waiting to be awoken.
你好，提姆
Hello, Tim.
佢识你？
He knows you?
你同哈利嘅Pikachu做咗拍档
I see you've partnered with Harry's Pikachu.
连我都识
And he knows me, too.
你识哈利？
You knew Harry?
哈利查𠮶单案⋯
The case Harry was working on,
系由我委托
it was for me.
真系曲折离奇！好曲折！
That's a twist. That's very twisty.
呢种化合物　威胁我建立嘅一切
This compound threatens everything I've built.
佢都知R呢单嘢，佢点会知？
He knows about the R. How does he know about the R?
我拜托哈利帮我查出来源
I hired Harry to trace it to its source.
最后嘅答案令我好惊讶
Imagine my shock when the answer
元凶竟然系我个仔
turned out to be my own son.
我毕生费尽心血　保护人类同Pokémon之间嘅和谐
I've devoted my life to perfecting the partnership
between Pokemon and humans.
因为Pokémon可以　启发我哋变得更好
A partnership where Pokemon bring out the best in us.
但系我忽略咗　身为父亲嘅责任
In doing so, I'm afraid I neglected
my responsibilities as a parent.
罗杰痛恨Pokémon
Roger resents the Pokemon.
我谂佢活喺我阴影下太耐⋯
I think he's lived in my shadow for so long,
决心要摧毁我嘅成就
he actually wants to destroy my legacy.
所谓「父亲」，冇父点有亲
Well, there's no such thing
as "daddy issues" without "daddy".
但系克里佛先生　你点可以容许佢咁做？
But, Mr. Clifford, how could you let him do that?
自从我因病要坐轮椅⋯
Ever since my illness put me in this chair,
罗杰就开始接掌公司大权
Roger has taken over more and more of the company.
佢操控咗董事会　警察同政客都听佢指挥
He controls the board.
He also controls the police and the politicians.
而且传媒都属于佢
And he owns the press.
我可以相信嘅只有哈利
Harry is the only one I can trust.
所以你要去揾佢
That's why you need to find him.
你冇听到消息
You haven't heard.
哈利已经死咗
Harry's dead.
你错喇，提姆
Oh, no, Tim.
你爸爸⋯
Your father
尚在人间
is alive.
小心呀！
Look out, kid!
先进全息投影
Advanced holographic imaging.
自从我要依靠轮椅⋯
Since being confined to this chair,
我一直投资研究方法　将世界带嚟我面前
I've invested in ways of bringing the world to me.
投影系用警方影像档重组
This was recreated from police footage.
可以睇到佢哋睇唔到⋯
It allows us to see things that they cannot
或者唔想我哋睇到嘅细节
or don't want us to see.
佢未死
He's alive.
Pika
Pika.
系我，我同哈利一齐撞车
It's me. I was with Harry in the crash.
我要去救佢
He needs my help.
如果哈利未死　点解冇人揾到佢？
If Harry's alive, why didn't they find him?
系咩嚟？
What is that?
系超梦
Mewtwo.
人类创造嘅妖孽
A man-made abomination
实验室里面用古代梦幻嘅化石　内藏嘅基因重组而成
created in a laboratory using DNA
from the fossil remains of the Ancient Mew.
难以置信
I can't believe it.
如果佢喺嚟自梦幻⋯
If that thing came from Mew,
肯定佢就会系　全世界最强嘅Pokémon
then we're looking at
the most powerful Pokemon in the world.
系喇！原来系咁
That's it. That's what happened to me.
超梦消除咗我嘅记忆
Mewtwo wiped my memory.
但系点解咁做？
But why?
等阵！
Wait, wait, wait!
等阵，佢带咗佢去边？
Wait. Wait, wait. Where did it take him?
呢点要靠你调查
That's for you to solve now.
揾到超梦，就会揾到你爸爸
Find Mewtwo and you will find your father.
人生好少有第二次机会
Second chances
are special things, kid.
破到呢单案系好事
There's a lot we can make better if we crack this case.
但系我有一个问题　我哋去紧边？
One question, though. Where are we going?
我唔知，我负责行　你负责指挥，你先系神探
I don't know, I'm just going.
You gotta tell me where. You're the detective.
好，如果核心人物　系罗杰克里佛⋯
Okay. If Roger Clifford is the key to all of this…
就要揾个　可以接触到佢嘅人
Then we need someone who has access to him.
唔使讲都知系边个啦，大情圣
And we both know who that is, lover boy.
够喇，唔好再讲呢样
Okay, come on, that's…
Come on. Let's not start that again.
佢嚟喇
There she is.
搞咩戴黑超　佢见唔见到我哋？
What's with the sunglasses? Can she see us?
佢点会见到我哋
I don't think she can see us.
﹣多谢妳嚟　　﹣咪同我讲嘢
- Hey. Thanks for coming.    - Don't talk to me.
好
Okay.
﹣而家点？　　﹣举止自然啲
- What happens now?    - Just act casual.
唔好望我
But don't look at me.
成件事一啲都唔自然
There's nothing really casual about this.
你睇呢份档案
Look at this.
唔好意思，系我衰
- Oh, shit.    - Sorry. That was my fault.
唔好意思⋯
- Ow!    - Sorry. I'm sorry.
真系好有火花　直接叫佢过嚟坐啦
Oh, this is working out great.
Why don't you just have her sit over here.
不如一齐坐？
You wanna just come sit with us?
我唔应该鼓励你　你唔会有机会
I should never have encouraged you.
You have no chance.
﹣我开咗罗杰部电脑　　﹣咁劲，点做到？
I got access to Roger's computer.
Oh, wow, how'd you do that?
﹣倒杯咖啡落佢大脾　　﹣真系浪费
Spilled a cappuccino on his lap.
Eh, that sounds like a waste of coffee.
我起咗佢底　尤其是佢喺呢一带嘅物业
I searched through all his records.
I targeted the property rights in the region
然后比对市政局记录　佢家族资助嘅公司，终于揾到⋯
and I cross-checked that with city records
for any Clifford-financed businesses until I found it.
呢间机构PCL
May I present PCL:
一间Pokémon基因研究所，唔止咁
A Pokemon genetic research facility.
But that's not all.
佢有啲料到
She's good.
上个礼拜，PCL发生「意外」　全部设施都要关闭
Last week, PCL had an "accident"
and had to shut down their entire facility.
正正系哈利古德曼失踪𠮶晚
That's the same night Harry Goodman went missing.
冇人知道发生咩事
No one knows what happened.
传媒完全冇报导
Total media blackout.
咩意思？
What does it all mean?
我唔知，但系我好兴奋
I don't know. This is very exciting.
﹣你兴唔兴奋？　　﹣兴奋
- Are you excited?    - Yeah.
佢好似兴奋到尿渗
I think he just peed a little.
搞错咗，尿渗嘅系我
Oh, nope. That's me. That was me.
所以呢单嘢有内幕？
So, um, there's a cover-up?
Mmm-hmm.
佢哋想隐瞒啲咩？
But, er, what are they covering up?
我哋去查个究竟
What do you say we go find out?
等我搞清楚先
So let me get this right.
我哋被迫听呢啲水疗音乐　费事你爆炸，炸死我哋
We're forced to listen to this spa music
so your head doesn't explode and kill us all.
可达
Psyduck.
你嘅Pikachu好特别
Your Pikachu is so unusual.
可达
Psyduck.
放低你只脚　我系唔会帮你按摩
Hey, you put that down. I am not giving you a massage.
可达
Psyduck.
我未见过Pokémon会戴帽
I have never known a Pokemon to wear a hat.
佢系好怪，好鬼怪
Yeah, he's weird. He's so weird.
﹣可达　　﹣我梗系关心拍档生死
Psyduck.
Of course I care about my partner's life.
得喇，伸只脚过嚟
Fine, fine. Hand it over.
﹣你搞乜呀？　　﹣咩事？
What are you doing?
What?
冇嘢，我只系好奇⋯佢系边个
Nothing.
（路伦博士因争议性研究失去职位）
I was actually wondering who this was.
PCL首席科学家，安妮路伦博士
It's PCL's chief scientist, Dr. Anne Laurent.
个唔著衫友讲嘅实系佢
I bet this is the doctor Shirtless was talking about.
佢嘅Pokémon实验　被大学撤销拨款
She lost her university grant
over experimentation of Pokemon
因为佢尝试精神控制Pokémon
because she was trying to control their minds.
Oh, wow.
佢基本上系Pokémon精神学家
She's essentially a neurologist for Pokemon.
或者佢会知道　畀人绑喺炸弹旁边
Maybe she could weigh in
on the long-term psychological effects
会有咩长期精神影响
of being strapped into a baby seat
- next to a bomb.    - Hmm?
到喇
This is it.
你睇啲警告牌
Look at the signs.
（禁止进入 剧毒物质）
肯定系好大件事
Must have been a really bad accident.
就系想你咁谂
That's what they want you to believe.
装假狗嘅人好高招
Whoever staged this did an excellent job.
标志肯定吓走晒啲傻仔
Those signs are the perfect scarecrow for suckers.
我都畀佢哋吓到
Yeah, well, they're working on me.
呢条女想冒险
Kid, this dame's looking for danger.
你要得佢欢心　就要带佢去闯关
You want to win her over,
you gotta lead her straight to it.
首先，女人唔系一条条嘅
First of all, women don't like to be called "dame".
第二，女人钟意嘅系沉著冷静
Second, women appreciate calm, er, level-headed
负责任嘅判断
and responsible decision-making.
佢做咩？喂，喂！
What is she doing? Hey, hey!
喂！
Hey!
露丝，妳搞乜？
Lucy, what are you doing?
我要剪开铁丝网　开路入去
I'm, er, I'm cutting the fence so that we can slip through.
﹣妳去边度揾架生？　　﹣你咪理
Where did you get those?
Oh, don't worry about it.
﹣你先啦，请　　﹣可达
After you, sir.
唔制？好，我行先　总之你要冷静
- Psyduck.    - No? Okay.
I'll go first. Whatever's most calming.
可达
Hmm, Psyduck.
（紧急状态）
好
Okay.
可达，可达
Psyduck. Psyduck.
Oh.
唔紧要，你唔使落地
It's okay. You can stay up there.
我系有失忆症　都肯定呢个系史上最差嘅计划
I may have amnesia, but I'm pretty sure
this is the worst idea anyone's ever had.
系咩嚟？
What is that?
唔清楚
I'm not sure.
可达，可达
Psyduck. Psyduck.
系甲贺忍蛙
It's Greninja.
但系睇落唔对路
But they don't look right.
「测试22」
"Test 22."
（进化测试）　「力量强化」？
"Power enhancement"?
佢哋系实验对象
They were experimenting on them.
但系点解？
But why?
如果幕后黑手系罗杰克里佛　佢点解要揾Pokémon做实验？
If Roger Clifford's behind this,
what's he doing experimenting on Pokemon?
土台龟花园
A Torterra garden.
「Pokémon进化测试33　成长强化」
"Pokemon evolution test 33.
"Growth enhancement."
睇落大细冇乜唔妥
They look normal-sized to me.
可能未开始
Maybe it hasn't started yet.
佢哋好似想操控Pokémon进化
It's like they're trying to manipulate Pokemon evolution.
有可能咩？
Is that even possible?
我都唔知
I don't know.
不过我要记录一切
I need to document all of this, though.
你行先，我阵间跟上嚟
You go ahead. I'll catch up to you.
﹣妳肯定？　　﹣肯定
- Are you sure?    - Yeah.
Whoa.
呢度发生咩事？
What happened here?
肯定冇好嘢
Bad stuff.
非常唔妥
Really bad stuff.
仲认为危险标志系装假狗？
Still think this was staged?
细路，过嚟呀
Kid, hey! Over here.
系路伦博士部机
It says Dr. Laurent's station.
好似仲运作紧
Looks like it's still working.
开始遥控操作
Remote access initiated.
可达！
Psyduck!
大部分档案都损毁咗
Looks like most of the files are corrupted.
哎呀，又系全息投影
Uh-oh. Another one of those holograms.
第42日
Day 42.
经过多次尝试　我哋终于揾到一个稳定嘅方法
After much trial and error
we perfected a stable method
去抽取超梦嘅基因
to extract Mewtwo's DNA.
系超梦，等阵
It's Mewtwo. No, wait.
咪住，超梦嚟自呢度？
Wait, Mewtwo came from this place?
第60日，临床测试成功
Day 60. Clinical trials proven successful.
吸入剂导致混乱，而且　完全失去自由意志
The inhalant results in confusion
and the total loss of free will.
Pokémon因此野性大发
Which, in turn, makes the Pokemon go wild.
我哋将呢种化合物称为R血清
We've designated this chemical as serum R.
佢哋用超梦生产R
They used Mewtwo to make R.
然后喺对战场做测试
And they were testing it at the battles.
第68日
Day 68.
神经连结运作正常
The neural link is operational.
警告，红色警戒
Alert.
-Condition: Red. -Oh.
大件事⋯
No. No, no, no!
密闭室能源不足⋯
We're losing power in the containment…
﹣超梦一定系咁逃脱　　﹣终于有进展
That must've been how Mewtwo escaped.
Now we're getting somewhere.
﹣佢点解要针对哈利？　　﹣问得好
What did that thing want with Harry?
Good question, kid.
我试吓由头睇
I'll try and take us back to the beginning.
第1日，实验室差不多全面运作
Day 1. The lab is almostfully operational.
而家我哋只需要捕捉　人类史上最强嘅Pokémon⋯
All that remains now is to capture
the most powerful Pokemon known to mankind:
超梦
Mewtwo.
佢喺20年前由关东地区逃脱
It escaped nearly 20 years ago from the Kanto region.
好在我哋嘅金主　请咗一位专家揾佢
Fortunately, our benefactor's
hired a specialist to track it down.
祝你好运，古德曼警探
Good luck, Detective Goodman.
原来超梦捉走哈利　系要报复畀佢捉到
That's why Mewtwo took Harry.
It was revenge for being captured.
完全唔合理　哈利冇可能参与呢件事
This doesn't make any sense.
Harry would've never been a part of this.
我都想信，但系要面对现实
I wanna believe that, kid. But we gotta be honest here.
你多年冇见佢，我又失忆
You haven't seen him in years, and I got amnesia.
我哋根本唔清楚哈利份人
Neither of us can say for sure
what Harry would or wouldn't do.
我哋要快啲返入市区
We gotta get back to the city.
露丝，露丝，我哋要快啲返去⋯
Lucy. Lucy, we gotta get back to…
露丝？
Lucy?
之前冇呢挞嘢
That was not there before, kid.
小心后面
Look behind you.
Whoa!
拉火警钟！
Kid, the fire alarm!
﹣可达！　　﹣走喇，快啲！
Psyduck!
Come on! Let's go, let's go, let's go!
﹣可达！　　﹣返入去
- Psyduck!    - Whoa, whoa, whoa! Go back.
可达！
Psyduck!
趴低！
Get down!
可达！
Psyduck!
嚟啦！
Come on!
可达！可达！可达！　可达！可达！可达！
Psyduck! Psyduck! Psyduck!
可达！可达！可达！
达！达！达！
Duck! Duck! Duck!
可达！可达！可达！可达！
Psyduck! Psyduck! Psyduck! Psyduck!
﹣可达！　　﹣唔使惊，可达鸭，冇事嘅
- Psyduck!    - It's okay, Psyduck.
Everything's fine.
佢要爆喇
He's gonna blow his stack, kid.
唔使惊，可达鸭，冷静啲
It's okay, Psyduck, it's okay. Calm down.
可达！
Psyduck!
冇时间陪你头痛
This is no time
for your stupid headaches.
咪住，而家正正适合头痛
No, wait, this is the perfect time to get a headache.
﹣可达？　　﹣我好憎帮你按脚
- Psyduck?    - I hated rubbing your feet.
冷静啲，冷静啲！
Calm down, calm down!
我唔会原谅我双手帮你按脚
I'll never forgive my hands for what they did.
痛爆你个头啦，神经鸭！
Get a splitting headache now, you neurotic duck!
快啲爆！爆呀！爆呀！
Do it! Do it! Do it!
可达
Psyduck.
做得好，可达鸭，我顶帽呢？
Good job, Psyduck. Where's my hat?
有啲唔妥
Something's wrong.
唔系啩？
Is this really happening?
唔使担心
Don't worry.
可逹鸭嘅精神力量　令我哋产生幻觉
Psyduck's psionic waves are causing hallucinations.
唔系真嘅
None of this is real.
系真㗎！走呀！
Nope.
All of this is real! Run!
Go, go, go!
﹣发生咩事？　　﹣快啲走！
- What's happening?    - Let's go! Let's go!
搞成咁，仲有边个唔信气候变化？
At this point,
how could you not believe in climate change?
﹣死喇！　　﹣有我接住
Oh no, no, no!
I got you.
提姆！
Tim!
走喇！
Go! Run! Run!
快啲！
Go, go, go, go!
走快啲！
Go, go, go!
跳
Okay.
我哋冇死
We made it.
我好鬼憎呢个森林
I officially hate this forest.
提姆！
Tim!
露丝！
Lucy!
提姆！
Tim!
可达！
Psyduck!
就嚟冇路走
Kid, the walls are closing in.
要快啲谂办法
We have to do something and we gotta do it fast.
我要跳过去
I gotta jump for it.
呢个E计划唔错　谂咗ABCD先啦
That's a great fifth option. Let's work on the first four.
﹣你跳唔到咁远！　　﹣冇得拣
- You're not gonna make it!    - There's no other choice.
我哋大把选择　但系跌死咗就⋯
We have a lot of choices.
Falling to our death is not one of…
提姆！
Tim!
出力拉呀！
Pull, pull, pull!
出力爬！
Come on!
我以为⋯我以为我⋯
I thought I was gonna… I thought I was gonna…
我⋯我⋯
I… I…
我见到眼球
Eyeball.
眼球，眼球！
Eyeball. Eyeball!
我明啦！
Oh! I get it!
我明啦，呢个唔系森林
I get it now. This isn't a forest at all.
成个都系土台龟花园
This is the Torterra garden.
Pikachu！
Pikachu!
可达
Psyduck.
佢受咗伤
He's hurt.
﹣佢点呀？　　﹣我唔得喇
- Is he okay?    - I'm in bad shape, kid.
我喺度呀，拍档，我喺度
I'm here, partner. I'm here.
你头先叫我拍档？
Did you just call me partner?
梗系，你系我拍档
Yeah, of course. You're my partner.
冇错，你⋯
Yeah, that's right. You've, er…
你实撑我嘅
You've got my back.
喂⋯老友
Hey, hey, hey. Bud.
喂⋯Pikachu！
Hey! Hey, Pikachu!
Pikachu！
Pikachu!
唔好
No.
喂，救命呀！
Hey! Hey, help!
求吓你！
Please!
唔该
Please.
佢受咗伤
He's hurt.
唔该你
Please.
佢听唔明你讲咩
He doesn't know what you're saying.
但系佢明我感受
But he knows what I'm feeling.
我要带Pikachu去揾治疗Pokémon
I need to get Pikachu to a healer Pokemon.
唔该你
Please.
我求吓你
I'm begging you.
我唔想连佢都冇埋
I don't wanna lose him, too.
唔紧要
It's okay.
Hmm?
提姆，你睇吓
Tim, look.
好啦
Okay.
我返上车等你
I'll meet you at the car.
拍档，你会冇事㗎
You're gonna be okay, partner.
呢度？
Here?
咪住，等阵！
Hey! Wait, wait, wait!
你哋去边呀？
Where are you going?
我应该点做？
What am I supposed to do?
我等咗你好耐
I've been waiting for you.
超梦
Mewtwo.
唔好呀！
No, no, no! No, wait!
我喺边？
Where am I?
你冇事！
You're okay!
系呀
Yeah.
我唔知点解冇晒事
Somehow, I'm fine.
你遵守诺言　带佢个仔嚟见我
You brought the son to me, as agreed.
佢讲紧咩？
What is he talking about?
我唔知，我都一头雾水
I don't know, kid. I'm as lost as you are.
我爸爸喺边？
Where's my father?
你对佢做咗咩？
What'd you do with him?
警告
- Alert.    - Oh.
密闭室能源不足
We're losing power in the containment chamber.
你做得好好
You've done well.
人类系邪恶嘅
Humanity is evil.
我一直相信Pokémon⋯
I've always believed Pokemon are…
唔好！唔好！
No!
唔好！
等阵！
Wait, wait, wait!
Pikachu！等阵
Pikachu! Wait.
咪行住，我哋要倾吓
Hey. Slow down. We have to talk about this.
你要自己一个查落去
You have to go on without me.
咩话？咩意思？
What? What are you saying?
罗杰捉咗超梦　超梦捉咗我阿爸
Roger has Mewtwo. Mewtwo has my father.
我哋时间无多　要快啲破案
We're running out of time. We have a case to solve.
已经破咗　我知自己系边个
We already solved mine. I know who I am.
系我背叛哈利
I'm the guy who betrayed Harry.
我哋都唔肯定
We don't know that.
大家有眼见　我背叛咗你老窦，即系⋯
We both saw it. I betrayed your father. Which means
我都可以背叛你
I could betray you, too.
你唔会，我唔在乎见到咩
You wouldn't do that. I don't care what I saw.
﹣我知道你嘅本性　　﹣你点知？
- I know who you are.    - How do you know?
因为我⋯
Because, I…
我骨子里感觉到
I can feel it in my jellies.
我之前乱讲，骨子里冇嘢　我都系个假象
I… I made that up.
There's no jellies. There's no me.
我唔信
I don't believe that.
你靠自己好过
You're better off on your own.
﹣放开我！　　﹣我需要你，唔该
- Come on, Pikachu…    - No! No!
I need you. Please.
﹣你要远离我，系为你好　　﹣唔得，我唔畀你走
You have to stay away. It's for your own good.
No. I'm not letting you go.
见到啦？
You see?
我控制唔到　我会伤害需要我嘅人
I can't help it.
I hurt the people who need me.
呢个系我本性
That's who I am.
对唔住
I'm sorry.
好对唔住
提姆
Tim.
佢去边呀？
Where's he going?
发生咩事？
Hey, what happened?
Pikachu冇事嘛？
Is Pikachu okay?
佢好大件事
No, he's not.
走喇，我哋返去市区
Let's go. We gotta get back to the city.
Okay.
行喇
Come on.
莱姆市十周年Pokémon大巡游　即将于今日下午开始
The 10th anniversary
Ryme City Pokemon parade is set to begin this afternoon.
整个城市都聚集到市中心　准备参加庆祝活动
The whole city is converging on downtown
to watch the day's festivities.
我唔知你两个搞咩　但要快啲谂计，等阵！
I don't know what happened between you two,
but we need to strategize. Wait!
你去边呀？我哋要公诸于世　呢单系大新闻
Where are you going?
We need to tell the public what we found.
你去边呀？我哋要公诸于世　呢单系大新闻
This is breaking news.
系妳要去发布消息
No. No, you should break the news. You.
我要去揾霍华德
I'm gonna go talk to Howard.
点揾？
How…
提姆！
Tim!
新闻台老板就系新闻主角　我点报导呀？
How am I supposed to break the news
when the guy who runs the news is the breaking news?
预备，仙妮亚，5、4、3⋯
Okay, Cynthia. We're live in five, four, three…
留喺车入面，听话
Stay in the car, okay?
可达！
Psyduck!
（克里佛企业）
麦美丝小姐　我系见习生露丝
Mrs. McMaster. Hi, it's Lucy Stevens,
- the intern.    - Oh.
﹣CNM𠮶个　　﹣可唔可以⋯
- At CNM?    - Could you…
我有单大新闻　要讲畀民众听
Yeah. Erm, I have a story
that's really important that the people need to hear.
希望妳可以报导，我要⋯
And I was really hoping you could help me tell it.
I just need--
帮我买杯咖啡，鲜奶、特浓
Lucy, please. Take my coffee order.
Flat white, extra shot.
冇问题，仙妮亚
You got it, Cynthia.
「走访疆与界」
♪Searching far and wide♪
「⋯教Pokémon清楚⋯」
♪Teach Pokemon to understand♪
「⋯内里的力量⋯」
♪The power that's inside♪
「⋯Pokémon！」
♪Pokemon!♪
「⋯将他们收服！」
♪Gotta catch 'em all♪
「⋯是你和我⋯」
♪It's you and me♪
「⋯我知道这是我们的命运！」
♪I know it's my destiny♪
「⋯Pokémon！」
♪Pokemon!♪
咩嚟？
What… What is this?
我记得呢度
I know this place.
呢度系车祸现场
This is the scene of the crash.
𠮶啲系⋯？
What is that?
甲贺忍蛙嘅飞镖
Greninja stars.
一定系罗杰　指派甲贺忍蛙造成车祸
Roger must have sent the Greninjas
to cause the crash. Which…
咁即系⋯
Which means…
超梦系想保护我哋？
Mewtwo was trying to protect us?
先进全息投影
Advanced holographic imaging.
可以睇到佢哋睇唔到⋯
It allows us to see things that they cannot
或者唔想我哋睇到嘅嘢
or don't want us to see.
等阵，霍华德个全息投影肯定见到
Wait, Howard would have seen this in his hologram.
弊啦⋯
Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
提姆！
Tim!
霍华德！克里佛先生！你个仔⋯
Howard! Mr. Clifford! Your son,
佢捉咗超梦返嚟
he has Mewtwo here.
﹣等阵，点解你⋯　　﹣提姆
- Wait, why do you…    - Tim.
唔使怕
It's gonna be okay.
走呀！
Run!
唔系啩
No.
转移成功咗
The transfer worked.
我个身体仲坐住轮椅
My body is in the chair,
但系我嘅精神　已经进入超梦
but my mind is in Mewtwo.
霍华德？
Howard?
做得好，提姆
Well done, Tim.
你同哈利嘅Pikachu　带我揾返超梦
You and Harry's Pikachu led me straight to Mewtwo.
唔系超梦导致车祸
Mewtwo didn't cause the crash.
你爸爸明明可以拎钱走人
All your father had to do
was take the money and walk away.
但系佢偏偏要质疑我　我唯有阻止佢
But he started asking questions.
I had to stop him.
你想杀佢灭口！
You tried to kill him!
我别无选择
I had no choice.
佢追踪R去到对战场　最后揾到路伦博士
He tracked the R to the battles,
traced it back to Dr. Laurent.
然后仲夹埋Pikachu　帮超梦逃走
And then he and his Pikachu helped Mewtwo escape.
今日出席人数　非常令人满意
So, as you can see,
we are more than happy with the turnout today.
好多人一家大细⋯
So many families…
多谢各位，访问到此为止，多谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
That's all for today. Thank you.
唔好意思，借过，你好
Excuse me, please. Hello. Hi.
﹣我约咗市长做访问　　﹣入去啦
I have an interview with the mayor.
- Go on through.    - Thank you.
市长先生　我有要事同你倾，好紧急
Mr. Mayor, I need to speak with you, please. It's urgent.
﹣而家做访问，会唔会太迟？　　﹣唔该你！
A little late for an interview, don't you think?
Please!
巡游开始之前，首先要感谢　赞助今日盛事嘅霍华德克里佛先生
Before we begin the parade,
I'd like to thank our benefactor,
巡游开始之前，首先要感谢　赞助今日盛事嘅霍华德克里佛先生
Howard Clifford.
我目的从来唔系要医好自己
This was never about curing me.
我揾到人类未来道路
I have found a path forward for all of us.
超梦有能力将人类灵魂　注入Pokémon体内⋯
Mewtwo has the power
to transfer the soul of a human
超梦有能力将人类灵魂　注入Pokémon体内⋯
into the body of a Pokemon,
只要Pokémon　处于狂乱状态
as long as the Pokemon are in a crazed state.
有咗R气体　问题就得到解决
The R gas takes care of that.
啲气球，气球入面系R气体
The balloons. The R gas is in the balloons.
莱姆市各位市民！
People of Ryme City!
我终于揾到解药
I've finally discovered a cure.
唔单只可以医好我⋯
Not just for me,
仲可以医好全人类！
but for all of humanity!
Pokémon可以进化成　更理想嘅形态
Pokemon can evolve into better versions of themselves.
如今大家都可以！
And, now, so can you!
人类同Pokémon合为一体！
Humans and Pokemon merged into one!
唔好畀Pokémon吸入紫色气体！
Don't let your Pokemon breathe the purple gas!
快啲走，离开呢度！
Come on! Get out of here!
我系吉田，要求增援！
This is Yoshida requesting backup!
所有单位前往⋯
All units should proceed to the…
布鲁，唔好！
Snubbull, no!
唔好畀Pokémon吸入气体！
Don't let your Pokemon breathe the gas!
唔好畀Pokémon⋯
Don't let your Pokemon…
唔好吸入气体！
Oh, no! Don't breathe the gas!
话畀佢哋知！
Tell them!
露丝史提芬报告，全市进入紧急状态　千祈唔好畀Pokémon吸入⋯
This is Lucy Stevens reporting a citywide emergency.
Do not let your Pokemon breathe…
可达鸭，唔好呀！
Psyduck, no! Don't!
可达，可达，可达！
Psyduck, Psyduck. Psyduck!
可达？
Psyduck?
睇嚟系⋯　有史以来最差嘅巡游
Okay. Worst parade I've ever seen.
﹣可达　　﹣露丝，露丝，你喺入面？
- Psyduck.    - Lucy. Lucy, you're in there?
﹣提姆去咗边？　　﹣可达，可达
- Where's Tim?    - Psyduck. Psyduck.
﹣霍华德变咗超梦？　　﹣可达，可达
- Howard is Mewtwo?    - Psyduck. Psyduck.
我喺桥上嘅发现　即刻相形见绌
This really blows my bridge discovery out of the water.
好啦，我要阻止呢一切
All right, I gotta stop this.
开波！
Game on!
好啦，Pikachu　你系有能力
Okay, Pikachu, your powers are in there somewhere.
只系要啲火花挞著佢，嚟啦
Just need a little spark
to get this party started. Let's do this.
哈利嘅Pikachu
Harry's Pikachu.
你以为你可以阻挡未来？
You think you can stand in the way of the future?
我就系未来！
I am the future!
佢返咗嚟！
He's back!
神经连结
The neural link.
罗杰？
Roger?
后面呀！
Behind you!
你系百变怪
You're a Ditto.
百变怪
Ditto.
靠左！靠右！右呀！
Bank left! Bank right! Right!
你喺地下学飞㗎？
Where did you learn how to fly? The ground?
等阵，等阵！咪住先！
No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop! Wait, wait, wait!
咪住先！
Wait, wait, wait!
咪咁啦，好唔公平
Come on. No. That's not fair.
警告你
For the record, I have no guilt
我唔会对我嘅　怪鸡眼版女神留手
hitting a beady-eyed version of the woman
I'm very attracted to.
向上飞，唔好索啲气体
Uh-oh! Pull up, pull up. Don't breathe the gas.
你系咪索晒？
You breathed the gas, didn't you?
好嘢！
Yeah!
收拾佢，百变怪！
Finish him, Ditto!
百变怪！
Ditto!
唔好，唔好呀！
No! No, no, no, no!
Pikachu！
Pikachu!
提姆！
Tim!
哈利个仔玩完喇！
Harry's son is finished!
未完，提姆叫我用伏特攻击
No. Tim said Volt Tackle's my best move.
我哋就认真嚟一次　Pokémon对战！
Let's do this Pokemon battle thing right.
唔好
No.
好嘢！
Yeah!
伸手畀我！伸手畀我！
Give me your hand! Give me your hand!
𠮶只百变怪有冇咁劲呀？
What kind of a Ditto was that?
佢系我老窦嘅基因实验
That was one of my father's genetic experiments.
可达
Psyduck. Ditto.
百变怪⋯
Ditto…
简直螳臂挡车
A feeble effort.
Pikachu冇可能打赢超梦
A Pikachu cannot defeat Mewtwo in battle.
我唔使打赢你
I didn't need to defeat you.
只需要分散你注意力
I just needed to distract you.
Huh.
唔好！
No!
你做咗咩？
What have you done?
Pikachu！
Pikachu!
唔好！
No!
﹣Pikachu！　　﹣提姆！
- Pikachu!    - Tim!
你冇嘢嘛？
- Oh!    - Are you okay?
对唔住，你最需要我嘅时候　我推开咗你
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I pushed you away
just when you needed me the most.
我好高兴你返咗嚟⋯
I'm just happy you're back…
拍档
partner.
话我知，你可以修正一切
Please tell me you can fix this mess.
我会令一切恢复原状
I will undo what has been done.
以后唔好再试，好嘛？
Let's never do that again, okay?
最奇怪嘅系　无论佢有几多缺点⋯
The strange thing is that, no matter what his flaws,
到头来⋯
deep down,
我都系怪责自己　冇好好陪佢
I blame myself for not being there for him.
妳之前就调查呢单消息　冇人知道前已经有线索
You. You were working on this story.
Had a lead on it before anyone else even knew.
﹣冇错　　﹣好，我要妳上镜
That's correct.
Good. Right, you're going on camera.
我要妳今晚黄金时段　主持CNM专题报道
I want you giving an in-depth report
for CNM tonight, primetime.
记住最后要讲⋯
And make sure you close with:
「罗杰克里佛承诺弥补　佢父亲做成嘅祸害⋯」
"Roger Clifford pledges to undo
all the harm his father caused
「就由被实验嘅Pokémon开始」
starting with the Pokemon he experimented on."
我哋竟然成功咗
I can't believe we did it.
可达
Psyduck.
做得好，你冷静啲先　定啲嚟，好啦
Great work. Hey, calm down. Stay calm. Okay.
希望以后唔好再见
Oh, I hope we never
- get to see each other again.    - Hmm.
﹣今晚夜啲见？　　﹣掂，我系指⋯好呀
- Meet me later tonight?    - Cool. I mean, yeah.
好
Okay.
嚟啦
Come on.
Psyduck. Psyduck. Psyduck.
叻仔呀，提姆
Way to go, Tim.
我仲有一件事要修补
There is one last thing I must fix.
我爸爸
My father.
你寻找嘅爸爸　一直都喺你身边
The father you have been looking for
has been with you all along.
佢讲咩？
What's he talking about?
我唔⋯
I don't…
Pika！
Pika!
Pikachu！
Pikachu!
你做得好好
You've done well.
人类系邪恶嘅
Humanity is evil.
但系你令我知道　并非全人类都邪恶
But you have shown me that not all humans are bad.
哈利古德曼，你嘅Pikachu　奉献肉体，拯救你嘅心灵
Harry Goodman,
your Pikachu offers its body to save your mind.
佢有个仔
There is a son.
个仔出现，我就可以复原爸爸
With the son's return, I can repair the father.
你嘅记忆会消失　但系你内心会知道自己系边个
Your memory will be gone,
but your heart will know who you are.
我带走呢个肉体　令你可以生存
I take this body so that you might live.
带个仔返嚟
Return with the son.
三号月台正在登车
Now boarding on track three,
453号北行列车
train 453 northbound.
细路！
Hey, kid!
婆婆会去接你车
Grams will meet you when you arrive.
好
Okay.
迟啲见
I'll see ya.
See ya.
Pika
Pika.
爸爸？
Hey, Dad?
系？
Yeah?
我可唔可以同你住多一排？
You think I can stay with you for a while?
当然好啦，细路
I'd like that, kid.
最好不过
Yeah, I'd like that very much.
我都觉
Me, too.
饮杯咖啡？
You wanna get a coffee?
好奇怪，我一路都想饮杯咖啡
It's the weirdest thing.
That's all I've been thinking about,
好奇怪，我一路都想饮杯咖啡
is having a coffee right now.
我应该要揾份新工
I think I'll have to find a new job.
系咩？你想做边行？
Oh, yeah? What are you thinking?
或者可以试吓做侦探？
Erm… maybe I could give detective work a try?
Pika﹣Pika！
Pika-Pika!
佢好似几钟意呢个提议㖞
I think he likes that idea.
《POKÉMON 神探 Pikachu》
译者：　Ivan Wong